Princess! Princess! Princess!
Princess!
Now!
Princess! Princess!
Enough.
The dead are the past.
The living can never interact with them.
Nothing comes of them
remaining in this world.
There’s nowhere for them to go.
So...
It's time for them to disappear.
That goes for you too,
doesn't it?
You're like me.
You also have nothing left.
No, you more than me...
You were planning on dying here,
weren't you?
So...
Why are you still alive?
It's your fault!
Everything is your fault!
Shin!
If it weren't for you...
Reaper!
You don't need to let me
hold you back anymore.
You can just forget about me.
No.
Wait.
Brother...
Breakfast time!
Hooray!
Shin!
Shin.
Thanks.
You have nothing.
Nothing to protect.
No place to go home to.
Thank you.
Nothing to wish for.
Nothing to aim for.
Thanks.
Shin, thank you.
Not even anyone
to call out for as you die.
Not a single reason to live.
Thank you, Shin.
You were kept alive only
so you could kill the Morpho.
Thanks!
Shin, thank you!
So if no place needs you anymore,
Thank you.
then there's no reason
for you to stay alive.
Shin.
No, forget that.
I'd appreciate it if you could remember me,
just once in a while.
When you're free,
when you're happy...
Just then...
Just once in a while.
"Free"? "Happy"?
Don't tell me what to do!
Not when you left me behind...
Why does every single one of them...
Leave me alone...
Die before me...
And then tell me that we're the ones
who fight to the end...
That that's what makes us
who we are...
You were looking for a place to die.
That's all.
And you took them with you
on your meaningless journey.
Shin.
Thank you!
Your heart's frozen cold.
That's why the warm feelings
you shared with your comrades burn you.
Are they too painful to bear?
Then we'll take them from you for a while.
Let us help for once!
We've left you alone again, haven't we?
Wait!
- Time Since Mission Began -
You thought it was over, didn't you?
You thought it would be over
when you killed the Morpho, right?
No more...
But...
Don't leave me!
now it's just me again.
Will you remember me?
But to tell the truth...
Kill me!
You've been waiting for this.
This moment.
I see that you are with
the San Magnolia Republic.
I am with the Giad Federacy
177th Mechanized Infantry Division.
I was conducting Legion elimination operations
to support our defense lines.
Thank you for your support.
No, but...
Why were you in this awful battle alone?
Thank you for your concern.
However, my main unit is behind me,
and I will be able to rendezvous with them.
Will you come with me?
Our main unit is capable of protecting you,
if your numbers aren't too large.
No.
I will stay in this country
and continue to fight.
I won't abandon it.
Even if I'm not strong enough to win...
I will continue to fight.
Fight? Why?
Are you in a hurry to die?
Then you would've done better
not to fight at all.
I'm fine.
If something happens,
make a run for it, my Queen!
Without any kind of protection,
you're just in the way if there's a fight!
No.
And we don't know that
something will happen.
Even if I'm not strong enough to win,
I won't embarrass myself
by giving up and falling to my knees.
I'll keep fighting until
the very last moment of my life.
I know people who lived that way,
and they believed that I could do the same.
So we...
So I...
will fight until I reach them,
and until I can take them to what lies ahead!
I am Captain Vladilena Milizé, the commander
of the former Republic's Defense Forces.
And I will never
run from this war!
Major...
Those people died a long time ago,
didn't they?
What duty do you have to the dead?
They told me not to forget.
They told me about what would happen.
About the Legion's large-scale assault.
And that's how I survived.
They wanted me to survive.
They told me they wanted
to see me again.
And that's why I can still fight.
So I want to be
who they thought
I could be.
They're gone now.
But I want to get to where they are.
To catch up to them...
And this time...
Fight with them.
Because... I want to take them
beyond this battlefield!
And you...
You're the same.
You fought to the end.
You survived.
That's why you're here now.
I think that's something
you should be more proud of.
Major...
Major, I...
Leave the rest to us.
Your Highness, this ain't good.
I just got word
from the guys at the Gran Mur.
There's Legion heading toward us!
No!
Federacy soldier, come with us!
No.
Impossible...
No, but...
Cyclops?
You didn't see it?
That marking...
That's the Giad Empire's mark, right?
No...
Oh, right…
I guess there’s no way
you could've ever seen it.
Good work, Lieutenant.
Thank you.
You okay, Lieutenant Nouzen?
Lieutenant Colonel...
You're alive.
Thanks to you.
I was worried about you.
If you've finished your mission,
it's your job to give me a report.
I'm sorry.
This time, the others gave me the report.
There were survivors?
Shin!
Listen, that should’ve been
the first thing you asked!
Really. Kurena was bawling
her eyes out again.
She said you were the only one
she couldn't reach.
This is the second time
you've made her cry!
You need to stop being so reckless.
I'm not crying!
Commander, don't just
write us off for dead!
That's right!
You got blown away
and stopped moving.
So we thought you were dead.
We were a little worried.
So, miraculously, the whole unit's safe!
Nobody left you behind!
Good work, Shin.
You're still around, Ernst?
Huh? I'm just worried about my son!
Do you have to be so mean?
I'm the supreme commander
of the allied armies, you know!
Why wouldn't I be around?
Our advance teams tell me
you've already made contact,
but after this operation ends,
Federacy forces will begin a rescue operation
in former San Magnolia territory.
Autonomous units intercepted transmissions
from within the Republic,
and the three nations
made the decision jointly.
If another Morpho is ever made,
it would be a serious threat if it was able
to hide in highly-defended Republic territory.
And...
It would be unethical to know
there were survivors and leave them to die.
To the Federacy, they are comrades.
This is a rescue operation,
the same as what we did for you Eighty-Six.
We're glad to do it.
But it's not a home
you want to go back to, right?
If you don't want to fight
for the sake of your oppressors,
we'll let you head back
when we advance.
No, we'll remain with the army.
I have no desire
to save the Republic,
but there are people there
who I don't want to die.
I see.
What will happen
to the Republic forces I just met?
Our helicopters will take
them to the Gran Mur.
Escort helis will protect them
if they run into Legion.
So let our advance teams take over
while you rest for a while.
Roger.
And Frederica, you're in for one hell
of a punishment when you get home.
I'll throw her in a container
or something and send her back.
Shinei? You're betraying me?!
Thanks, big brother.
I'm not heading home even after
we meet up with the main unit.
I don't need a hostage anymore.
So it seems.
I'm amazed you're safe.
Kiri...
protected me.
But... I'm sorry.
The gun you gave me...
Oh, it's fine.
In the end, it was just an excuse
to go back to the battlefield.
You're still carrying them,
every single one.
How is it an excuse?
Fool.
You're a softie, Reaper.
You didn't want
to give her your name?
She was your commander
when you were in the Republic, right?
I never told you about the Major.
Did you forget my power?
You were eavesdropping?
When she gave her name,
you were so surprised!
I saw there must be some deep connection.
"Go on ahead," was it?
I'm glad she caught up with you.
She's come this far
out of respect for you.
Are you sure you didn't want
to give her your name?
I can't, no.
She said she was going
to catch up with me.
It wouldn't be right
if she caught up with me in this state.
When she goes forward, what she sees...
shouldn't be a battlefield like this.
I don't know what to say...
You're such a boy.
You can be so weirdly stubborn
when it comes to these things.
By the way, did you notice?
You have your answer.
If she's going forward,
there needs to be something for her
to see down the path she follows.
She follows the path that you create.
So what is your destination?
You just found the answer yourself,
didn't you?
Report.
They told me not to forget.
They told me about what would happen.
About the Legion's large-scale assault.
And that's how I survived.
They wanted me to survive.
They told me they wanted
to see me again.
And that's why I can still fight.
So how'd she look?
I couldn't see.
She didn't know it was you, right?
Yeah.
When did any of us say
not to forget?
Her voice was different.
She sounds bolder now.
Of course it's changed.
Just like us,
she fought and survived.
So much happened...
But I'm so glad!
Why are you crying?
I'm not crying!
She'd be surprised
if she knew we were alive.
I wish I could've met her, just once.
"Handler One."